Thomas Loch

Thomas_Loch@hotmail.com | linkedin.com/in/thomaslloch/ | +31 6 44 287 288 | thomasloch.nl

Summary

Embeded developer with a focus on quality. Latest experience include developing c++ applications for embeded linux devices, using QT, CMAKE, visual studio. With a strong focus on product quality by setting up and maintaining CI pipelines using Microsoft TFS, and incorperating and gathering large sets of data to improve/debug new features remotely. Previous experiences with cloud workflows of Microsoft, along with Azure Dev-Ops build pipelines. I have also worked in the electronic manufacturing industry, focusing on pcb development and manufacturing proficiency. Strong professional with a Bachelor of Aviation from Griffith University.

Education

2019, Working Talent, The Netherlands

IoT Masterclass

2018 - On Hold, University of Southern Queensland, Australia

Bachelor of Engineering (Honours) Majoring in Computer Systems GPA: 6.29

2009 - 2012, Griffith University, Australia

Bachelor of Aviation, Graduate Diploma of Flight Management GPA: 4.6

2007 - 2008, Metropolitan South Institute of TAFE

Certificate III in Computer Aided Drafting

2004 - 2008, Loganlea State High School

High School Certificate Year 12

Certificates

Microsoft 70-483 Programming in C#

Work Experience

03/2020 - Current, Euphoria Software (Cabman)

Embeded Developer

- Taximeter MDT (Mobile data terminal): Within a team of 6, we built up this new product to replace the aging solution currently in place. This new hardware evolution has has allowed for the intergrations of new technologies such as Bluetooth and NFC. As a team we have been resonible for getting the prouct ready for the Dutch regulations whilsts simultaniaesly developing new features to attract foreigh customers. Over the last few years i have become ever more interested in the quality of the product, through the use of device health monitoring, and suggesting and implementing code qualily controls and metrics. I also enjoy combing through large datasets to find and squash ever more elusive bugs.
- o Tools Used: C++, QT, CMAKE, Linux, Python, C#, SQL, Git, Scrum, TFS YAML pipelines.

03/2019 - 11/2019, Atos (via Working Talent)

IoT Developer

- Medical Smart Fridge: This project revolved around the tracking and tracing of medicine, through the use of RFID technology. The purpose was to keep tight control over controlled drugs, be able to pinpoint which fridge the medicine resides in, and keep track of expiration dates / storage conditions. I was responsible for hardware procurement, assembly, and programming.
- Connectivity Platform: This project aims to serve as a single cloud based point of access for various data sources. I become involved with the project as scrum master, and programmer for small battery operated hardware. I worked with various communication platforms such as LoRa, NB-IoT, and BLE (Bluetooth).
- o Tools Used: C#, ASP.NET Core, C++, Arduino, Git, Scrum, Azure, SQL, Azure devops pipelines.

11/2017 - 01/2019, Loch Engineering

Owner

- Design and assembly of custom mechanical keyboards
- o Tools Used: Altium Designer, KiCad, Autodesk Inventor, C#, C++, Git.

07/2016 - 11/2017, Pacific Data Systems Australia Pty. Ltd.

Production Technician | R&D Technician

- o Assembly and testing of company products, using machines and hand tools.
- Assembly of pcb's, using a pick and place machine (Autotronik BA385V2), and reflow oven.
- Assembly of small R&D pcb batches, using hand tools, down to 0402 sized components.
- Programming, fault finding and fixing of assembly and R&D pcb's.
- Designing circuit boards, to a strict set of design standards based on product needs.
- Maintaining an up to date inventory of all components, and upkeeping the BOM of all company electronic products.
- Making inhouse modbus testing software using C#
- Tools Used: Altium Designer, Autodesk Inventor, C#, Git.

11/2013 - 07/2016, Aldi

Trainee Store Manager (from 10/2014) | Workplace Health & Safety Officer

- Exceptional customer service.
- Responsibility of all store money.
- Ensuring shifts happen as scheduled, within operational guidelines at all times.
- o Staff training, and maintenance of standards among all staff.

Skills

Languages

- English
- Dutch

Computer software | languages

- o C/C++ Large code base >10 years old, that continues to intergrate new code practices
- C# Testing software using RS485/Modbus, ASP.NET dashboards
- Python/Bash/Powerschell Scripting to support projects and pipelines.
- Linux -
- SQL Large datasets with >2 million entries per day.
- Latex Product documentation, resumes & cover letters
- o Git multi team repos with many users.
- o Inventor 3d modelling and sheet metal design.
- HTML/JavaScript Basic website design, pure JavaScript
- Altium 2-4 layer design, down to 0402 size

Other

• I have run my own business designing and selling custom keyboards

Aviation

License

Commercial Pilot License 11/04/2012 | Training Completed at the Airline Academy of Australia Private Pilot License 18/07/2011 | Training Completed at the Airline Academy of Australia Total Flight Time: 240 Hrs | PIC: 80 Hrs

Rating & Endorsements

- Single Engine (<5,700 kg)
- Multi Engine Command Instrument Rating
- Beechcraft Duchess BE76
- Manual Propeller Pitch Control
- Retractable Undercarriage
- Tailwheel Undercarriage

References

Vincent Bekker

Head of development v.bekker@euphoria-it.nl

Guido van der Sluis

14.0 / IoT Business & Technology Consulting+31 6 3028 0307 | guido.vandersluis@atos.net

David Hugman

Production Manager, Pacific Data Systems Australia Pty. Ltd. +61 7 3361 2000 | dhugman@pacdatasys.com.au